<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Adam Kostarelas</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/</link><description>Recent content on Adam Kostarelas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© {year} Adam Kostarelas</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 20:20:26 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adam.kostarelas.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Okay Buddy skateboarding dog CTF writeup</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/okay-buddy-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 20:20:26 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/okay-buddy-2025/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve only done a handful of CTF challenges before and found that I&amp;rsquo;ve gravitated towards forensics, OSINT and some cryptography. This challenge was outside of my comfort zone, but I wanted to persist and try something new.
It&amp;rsquo;s fun when there&amp;rsquo;s a theme to a CTF, and skateboarding dog did an amazing job with the 2D pixelart and game.
Skateboarding dog CTF writeup Okay Buddy There&amp;rsquo;s a flag in the tree, and Buddy is so close to help us grab it.</description></item><item><title>Githubs reputation being exploited by bad actors to distribute malware</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/github-macos-malware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 18:42:13 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/github-macos-malware/</guid><description>Github has become popular over the years for a place where you can collaborate on open-source software, and download it too. This reputation can be abused to by bad actors, pretending that software is open source, when in reality they link to a compiled file, or to an external site.
Today I spotted one such that came up high in search results for macos audio There were two separate results that came up, im</description></item><item><title>Quad single IP addresses</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/quad-single-ip-addresses/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 17:20:23 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/quad-single-ip-addresses/</guid><description>Quad single IP addresses - think 1.1.1.1, &amp;hellip; 8.8.8.8, 9.9.9.9 Who owns them, and what are they used for?
Anyone who has tinkered around with DNS settings are familiar with a few like 1.1.1.1, 8.8.8.8 and 9.9.9.9 (Cloudflare, Google and Quad9). I&amp;rsquo;ll be including links and readouts of whois if you&amp;rsquo;re interested to find out more.
It is interesting to learn about IP addressing, and having recently completed FIT5037 at Monash, understanding BGP (Border Gateway Protocol) routing with ASN (Autonomous system numbers)</description></item><item><title>Arc Browser, how private is it?</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/arc-browser-privacy-check/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 11:20:23 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/arc-browser-privacy-check/</guid><description>This writeup looks into how Arc phones home to log analytics without giving users a good way to opt-out.
Arc browser is one of the many Browsers to run Chromium (Blink) which includes browsers like Microsoft Edge, Brave and Opera.
It however is unique, being one of the only browsers that requires you log in before using it.
Mandatory login Their argument: &amp;ldquo;Sync data, provide support&amp;rdquo; - Its a tough ask, no matter how you spin it to require your users to be logged in to a service before using it.</description></item><item><title>Ambient sound series</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/ambient/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 17:48:23 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/ambient/</guid><description>I like the idea of sitting in a workspace with headphones on whilst listening to ambient sounds. Picture this; low chatter, mugs clinking, steam, birds chirping. I instantly think of a coffee shop. It is generally known that the act of meditation provides a more positive mindset. My spin on the typical audioscape is to record and playback some sounds closer to home.
This includes:
Rain Native birds National parks Ocean sounds and more.</description></item><item><title>Awesome Aussie, an awesome list automated with Airtable</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/awesome-aussie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 17:48:23 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/awesome-aussie/</guid><description>Awesome lists are handy. They allow a community or individual to manage a simple list in a Readme in a Git repository. That means all the benefits of revision history, merging changes from different versions and other advantages of git are included.
Where I feel they can often come short is when the lists get a bit too long. Typically data is to the point and a list usually to provides a URL and a brief description of that resource.</description></item><item><title>HuTasker, Hugo X Airtable</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/hutasker-hugo-x-airtable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 17:48:23 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/hutasker-hugo-x-airtable/</guid><description>HuTasker HuTasker integrates Hugo, a Static Site Generator (SSG) with Airtable in a sample app. The end product was to create a mock marketplace for tasks, drawing inspiration from my previous startup Trunked and Airtasker. The technical goal was to use Hugo with a &amp;lsquo;back end&amp;rsquo; that can act as a content management system (CMS) through an API that can fill and manage data on its pages. I started the project making the assumption that my &amp;lsquo;client&amp;rsquo; wanted to manage their data in a spreadsheet that can control the front end.</description></item><item><title>Moving from NBN to 5G</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/from-nbn-to-5g/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 04:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/from-nbn-to-5g/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting a long time for NBN. Back to the original announcement, I remember the first time the address checker provided a date of installation. Delay after delay the day arrived, I&amp;rsquo;d have regular access to fast broadband.
Since then, so many innovations have changed the way we use technology on a daily basis. Having gone through a change in OS I was quickly thrust into the world of linux, homelabs and self hosting.</description></item><item><title>Journey into making Album Art covers</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/album-art/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/album-art/</guid><description>Ever since I got an iPod touch back in the late 2000s, a key design standout has been how Album art can provide bias to decide whether or not to listen to a song. It can also at times provide a &amp;lsquo;feeling&amp;rsquo; of the album. The feature i&amp;rsquo;m referring to of course is Cover flow:
During this lockdown in Melbourne, Victoria, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to do a few pieces of digital art to refine my photoshop skills, and to see it as a way to try to understand the &amp;lsquo;feeling&amp;rsquo; of music.</description></item><item><title>Mac privacy feature you may not have heard of</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/mac-privacy-feature/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 06:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/mac-privacy-feature/</guid><description>Many people who use a new Macbook in &amp;ldquo;Clamshell mode&amp;rdquo; (lid closed, and connected to an external display) may inadvertently be familiar with this privacy feature.
This innovative feature occurs when you close your Macbook&amp;rsquo;s lid. The microphone is then disconnected at a hardware level.
It is limited to Apple devices with the T2 chip:
All 13-inch MacBook Pro and MacBook Air notebooks with the T2 chip, all MacBook notebooks with a T2 chip from 2019 or later, and Mac notebooks with Apple silicon, this disconnect is implemented in hardware alone.</description></item><item><title>Turnip rice cake (腊味萝卜糕)</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/turnip-rice-cake/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/turnip-rice-cake/</guid><description>腊味萝卜糕 (Làwèi luóbo gāo) is a yum cha dish that is also popularly consumed during Lunar New Year. This version has a special twist, it is not the usual hong kong style however has an addition of a sea taste (seaweed).
Heads up, The moisture content of radish varies a lot, and can be difficult to cook..
Ingredients Chinese Sausage Lup Chong 腊肠 (We used this brand but you can use whatever is convenient) 1/2 pack 1 Turnip (500g) Sticky rice flour (2x 400g bags) Cornstarch (1x 400g bag) Dried shrimp (50g) Seaweed (5g) Dried scallop (50g) Shiitake mushroom (8 mushrooms, dried is recommended for the flavour.</description></item><item><title>NGV Trennial Visit 2021</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/ngv-trennial-2021-visit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/ngv-trennial-2021-visit/</guid><description>Trennial 2020 Visiting NGV has been close to the top of my to-do list of places to visit with the Melbourne lock-down slowly lifting.
This collection of photos are a few of the highlights on my visit.
The first feature is an animated work of art that uses a dataset of images of nature to base the colours of the mesmerising waves. Refik Anadol&amp;rsquo;s piece of art inspired me to add a new project to my list for a web based adaptation&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Easy Mac Quality of Life Improvements with Apps</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/easy-mac-quality-of-life-improvements/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/easy-mac-quality-of-life-improvements/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s easy to make life easier on your Mac with the aid of a few Mac Apps, as well as hidden features within MacOS. Here&amp;rsquo;s a few suggestions.
Better Touch Tool Drag windows around effortlessly Instead of clicking and dragging the Instead of clicking and dragging the title bar to move the window around, a simple trick is to turn on a keyboard shortcut. When your cursor hovers over a window, your press the button and easily move the window around, quickly and effortlessly.</description></item><item><title>Cloud gamer in Australia</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/aws-ec2-gaming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 05:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/aws-ec2-gaming/</guid><description>Why I sold my gaming PC to try cloud gaming Over the past few years, i haven&amp;rsquo;t played as many games online as I used to. Full disclosure, I grew up as a playstation kid, playing PS3 with friends over PC gaming (aside from Minecraft). The only attempts I&amp;rsquo;d previously had at &amp;lsquo;cloud&amp;rsquo; gaming was using remote play with my PS4 over mobile data, which was choppy at best.</description></item><item><title>Speeding up e-mails and ditching the MX server</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/mx-server-to-gmail-email-forwarder/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/mx-server-to-gmail-email-forwarder/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had enough with shared hosting. For years our domain, Kostarelas.com has been on shared hosting provided by Godaddy.
Previously, I was too young to take control of the administration of the domain, but today was the last straw, thanks to two step verification.
I was setting up a service on a new device that of course asked for a 2 step verification code. Usually with platforms like Gmail, Outlook and fast SMTP servers, you&amp;rsquo;d get a push notification instantly.</description></item><item><title>Noodle Mix 1: Chapagetti and Shin Ramyun</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/noodle-mix-chapagetti-shin-ramyun/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 17:48:23 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/noodle-mix-chapagetti-shin-ramyun/</guid><description>After recently watching the film Parasite, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get over the simple fact that it&amp;rsquo;s rather easy to mix noodle packets together. Why wasn&amp;rsquo;t I trying this sooner?
Deciding enough is enough, I jumped on the opportunity to make a combination of flavours some may deem strange, but feeling adventurous I grabbed two packets from the pantry and went to work.
My combo of choice; Chapagetti, a black bean style noodle, with Shin Ramyun, a sort of spicy soupy noodle.</description></item><item><title>:// Welcome</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/first-post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 14:12:12 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/first-post/</guid><description>Hey It&amp;rsquo;s only fair that I introduce myself. I&amp;rsquo;m Adam, from Melbourne in Australia! You&amp;rsquo;ll find me working on a few tech related things, or building solutions for local businesses. As of July 2020 I&amp;rsquo;m working on Topre with Daniel Augoustakis.
There are a few smaller projects that i&amp;rsquo;m tackling during this COVID period also that I may post about. The main areas which i&amp;rsquo;ll be posting are:
Food Code journey Brand journey General.</description></item><item><title>Safari Firefox Theme</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/projects/firefox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/projects/firefox/</guid><description>Firefox WhiteSur theme A MacOS &amp; Windows Firefox theme to look more like Big Sur Safari. (For Firefox 70+)
Description Aim is to make Firefox look more like MacOS Big Sur Safari.
This is a CSS theme adapted to work on MacOS from the Linux GTK theme.
Based on https://github.com/vinceliuice/WhiteSur-gtk-theme/tree/master/src/other/firefox (This is a quick modification, and is not written from scratch.)
Installation (MacOS) Download the latest release, or clone the repo above.</description></item></channel></rss>