<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tech on Adam Kostarelas</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/tags/tech/</link><description>Recent content in tech on Adam Kostarelas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© {year} Adam Kostarelas</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 18:42:13 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adam.kostarelas.com/tags/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Githubs reputation being exploited by bad actors to distribute malware</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/github-macos-malware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 18:42:13 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/github-macos-malware/</guid><description>Github has become popular over the years for a place where you can collaborate on open-source software, and download it too. This reputation can be abused to by bad actors, pretending that software is open source, when in reality they link to a compiled file, or to an external site.
Today I spotted one such that came up high in search results for macos audio There were two separate results that came up, im</description></item><item><title>Quad single IP addresses</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/quad-single-ip-addresses/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 17:20:23 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/quad-single-ip-addresses/</guid><description>Quad single IP addresses - think 1.1.1.1, &amp;hellip; 8.8.8.8, 9.9.9.9 Who owns them, and what are they used for?
Anyone who has tinkered around with DNS settings are familiar with a few like 1.1.1.1, 8.8.8.8 and 9.9.9.9 (Cloudflare, Google and Quad9). I&amp;rsquo;ll be including links and readouts of whois if you&amp;rsquo;re interested to find out more.
It is interesting to learn about IP addressing, and having recently completed FIT5037 at Monash, understanding BGP (Border Gateway Protocol) routing with ASN (Autonomous system numbers)</description></item><item><title>Arc Browser, how private is it?</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/arc-browser-privacy-check/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 11:20:23 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/arc-browser-privacy-check/</guid><description>This writeup looks into how Arc phones home to log analytics without giving users a good way to opt-out.
Arc browser is one of the many Browsers to run Chromium (Blink) which includes browsers like Microsoft Edge, Brave and Opera.
It however is unique, being one of the only browsers that requires you log in before using it.
Mandatory login Their argument: &amp;ldquo;Sync data, provide support&amp;rdquo; - Its a tough ask, no matter how you spin it to require your users to be logged in to a service before using it.</description></item><item><title>Awesome Aussie, an awesome list automated with Airtable</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/awesome-aussie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 17:48:23 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/awesome-aussie/</guid><description>Awesome lists are handy. They allow a community or individual to manage a simple list in a Readme in a Git repository. That means all the benefits of revision history, merging changes from different versions and other advantages of git are included.
Where I feel they can often come short is when the lists get a bit too long. Typically data is to the point and a list usually to provides a URL and a brief description of that resource.</description></item><item><title>HuTasker, Hugo X Airtable</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/hutasker-hugo-x-airtable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 17:48:23 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/hutasker-hugo-x-airtable/</guid><description>HuTasker HuTasker integrates Hugo, a Static Site Generator (SSG) with Airtable in a sample app. The end product was to create a mock marketplace for tasks, drawing inspiration from my previous startup Trunked and Airtasker. The technical goal was to use Hugo with a &amp;lsquo;back end&amp;rsquo; that can act as a content management system (CMS) through an API that can fill and manage data on its pages. I started the project making the assumption that my &amp;lsquo;client&amp;rsquo; wanted to manage their data in a spreadsheet that can control the front end.</description></item><item><title>Moving from NBN to 5G</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/from-nbn-to-5g/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 04:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/from-nbn-to-5g/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting a long time for NBN. Back to the original announcement, I remember the first time the address checker provided a date of installation. Delay after delay the day arrived, I&amp;rsquo;d have regular access to fast broadband.
Since then, so many innovations have changed the way we use technology on a daily basis. Having gone through a change in OS I was quickly thrust into the world of linux, homelabs and self hosting.</description></item><item><title>Mac privacy feature you may not have heard of</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/mac-privacy-feature/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 06:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/mac-privacy-feature/</guid><description>Many people who use a new Macbook in &amp;ldquo;Clamshell mode&amp;rdquo; (lid closed, and connected to an external display) may inadvertently be familiar with this privacy feature.
This innovative feature occurs when you close your Macbook&amp;rsquo;s lid. The microphone is then disconnected at a hardware level.
It is limited to Apple devices with the T2 chip:
All 13-inch MacBook Pro and MacBook Air notebooks with the T2 chip, all MacBook notebooks with a T2 chip from 2019 or later, and Mac notebooks with Apple silicon, this disconnect is implemented in hardware alone.</description></item><item><title>Easy Mac Quality of Life Improvements with Apps</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/easy-mac-quality-of-life-improvements/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/easy-mac-quality-of-life-improvements/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s easy to make life easier on your Mac with the aid of a few Mac Apps, as well as hidden features within MacOS. Here&amp;rsquo;s a few suggestions.
Better Touch Tool Drag windows around effortlessly Instead of clicking and dragging the Instead of clicking and dragging the title bar to move the window around, a simple trick is to turn on a keyboard shortcut. When your cursor hovers over a window, your press the button and easily move the window around, quickly and effortlessly.</description></item><item><title>Cloud gamer in Australia</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/aws-ec2-gaming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 05:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/aws-ec2-gaming/</guid><description>Why I sold my gaming PC to try cloud gaming Over the past few years, i haven&amp;rsquo;t played as many games online as I used to. Full disclosure, I grew up as a playstation kid, playing PS3 with friends over PC gaming (aside from Minecraft). The only attempts I&amp;rsquo;d previously had at &amp;lsquo;cloud&amp;rsquo; gaming was using remote play with my PS4 over mobile data, which was choppy at best.</description></item><item><title>Speeding up e-mails and ditching the MX server</title><link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/mx-server-to-gmail-email-forwarder/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/mx-server-to-gmail-email-forwarder/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had enough with shared hosting. For years our domain, Kostarelas.com has been on shared hosting provided by Godaddy.
Previously, I was too young to take control of the administration of the domain, but today was the last straw, thanks to two step verification.
I was setting up a service on a new device that of course asked for a 2 step verification code. Usually with platforms like Gmail, Outlook and fast SMTP servers, you&amp;rsquo;d get a push notification instantly.</description></item></channel></rss>