<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Adam Kostarelas</title>
    <link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Adam Kostarelas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© {year} Adam Kostarelas</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 04:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Speeding up e-mails and ditching the MX server</title>
      <link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/mx-server-to-gmail-email-forwarder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/mx-server-to-gmail-email-forwarder/</guid>
      <description>My Journey speeding up e-mails and ditching the MX Server I&amp;rsquo;ve had enough with shared hosting. For years our domain, Kostarelas.com has been on shared hosting provided by Godaddy.
Previously, I was too young to take control of the administration of the domain, but today was the last straw, thanks to two step verification.
I was setting up a service on a new device that of course asked for a 2 step verification code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noodle Mix 1: Chapagetti and Shin Ramyun</title>
      <link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/noodle-mix-chapagetti-shin-ramyun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 17:48:23 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/noodle-mix-chapagetti-shin-ramyun/</guid>
      <description>After recently watching the film Parasite, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get over the simple fact that it&amp;rsquo;s rather easy to mix noodle packets together. Why wasn&amp;rsquo;t I trying this sooner?
Deciding enough is enough, I jumped on the opportunity to make a combination of flavours some may deem strange, but feeling adventurous I grabbed two packets from the pantry and went to work.
My combo of choice; Chapagetti, a black bean style noodle, with Shin Ramyun, a sort of spicy soupy noodle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>:// Welcome</title>
      <link>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 14:12:12 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adam.kostarelas.com/blog/first-post/</guid>
      <description>hljs.initHighlightingOnLoad(); Hey It&amp;rsquo;s only fair that I introduce myself. I&amp;rsquo;m Adam, from Melbourne in Australia! You&amp;rsquo;ll find me working on a few tech related things, or building solutions for local businesses. As of July 2020 I&amp;rsquo;m working on Topre.design with Daniel Augoustakis to provide brand solutions at a full service capacity.
There are numerous smaller projects that i&amp;rsquo;m tackling during this COVID period also that I may post about. The main areas which i&amp;rsquo;ll be posting are:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>